Guide to the New York Committee for Occupational Safety and Health (NYCOSH) Records WAG.029
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
- Series III: Unprocessed Material, 1971-2011
  - Box 20, 1982-1992
    NYCOSH Mailings and Correspondence, Members/Unions/Board, Working Well: NYS/PEF Health & Safety Training Program, Labor/Management Health and Safety Survey, Review of Health and Safety Concerns, Alaska Health Project Booklet, Slides, National Education Association: Health and Safety Handbook, Helpline Directory, North American Free Trade Act, OSHA Reform, Safety and Health Spotlight, Newspaper Clippings, Directory of US House of Representatives, Congressional Correspondence, Election Material, Notes, Fliers, and Proposed Agendas, Senate Committee on Labor Reports, Newsletters and Brochures on OSHA Reform, WISCOSH Study, OSH Stats, Legislative Bills, OSHA Review Commission, Magazine Clippings, Rules and Regulations on Access to Records, Final Report on State Mandated and Other Worker Protection Programs, Right to Know and Occupational Safety and Health Newsletters
  - Box 21, 1985-1996
    Resource Manual: Chemical Emergency Response/Hazardous Waste, Health and Safety Bulletins, Handwritten Notes, Correspondence, Taskforce Member List, VDT User Bill of Rights, Fliers and Leaflets, Legal Memoranda, Workers' Compensation Committee Minutes, Repetitive Strain Injury Task Force, Newspaper Clippings, Workers' Memorial Day Guide, Workers' Comp Legislation and Notes, Correspondence, Poughkeepsie BBD, Administrative Inventory of Workers Comp in Various States, RSI Articles, Occupational Health Clinics, Office Hazards, Health and Safety Newsletters, VDT Information, Health Issues, and Legislation, Labor Studies: Advanced Seminar in Occupational Health and Safety, Office Hazards and Control Report, Nurses' Committee Memorandum, and City Health Information
  - Box 22, 1987-1997
    NYS Department of Labor Hazard Abatement Board: Occupational Safety and Health Training and Education Proposal, Resolutions, Sign-Up Sheets, Publicity Material, Correspondence, 2005 COSH Conference Agenda, Worker Safety News, WisCOSH Newsletters, the Politics of Workers' Compensation, New York City Right to Know Programs, Memoranda, Articles, and News: Community Right to Know Information, Discussion Topics for the Public (Drafts), Hazard Communication: Right to Know Pamphlets, Brochures, Proposals and Statement, Newspaper Clippings, Board of Inquiry Reports: Rules and Regulations, NYCOSH Memoranda, Education Centers, Organizational Charts, Pamphlets, Board Meeting Material and Notes, Asbestos Booklet, Indoor Air Research, Department of Health Files, Department of Labor PESH Program, NYS Occupational Safety and Health Training Program, Institute for Environmental Education and Justice, Clinton/Gore - OSH, Subcommittee on Violence in the Workplace, Wrongful Death Files, Workers' Compensation Roundtables, VDT Coalition Files and Veto, News Articles, DC 37 Contract, OSH Stats, Non-profit News, Occupational Health Clinics and Evaluation
  - Box 23, 1984-1992
    NYCOSH Outreach & Sales Printed Materials, Newspaper Articles and Press Releases, Department of Labor Proposals, Correspondence from Department of Intergovernmental Affairs, New York Committee for Occupational Safety and Health Budget, Hazard Recognition and Control Study, NYSUT Contract, Department of Labor Forms, Conference and Meeting Materials, Financial Records and Balance Sheets, NY Committee for Occupational Safety and Health, Teacher Grant Proposal, AFL-CIO News, Transformer Files, Occupational Safety Training/Education Contracts, Summary of Work Program and Budget, Asbestos Reports and OSHA Files, Electronic Workers of America Files, Wilson-Shriver Grievances, Spanish Fact Sheet, Local Files: Firefighters, Graphics
  - Box 24
    Correspondence Outgoing and Incoming, Meeting Files, Civil Court Information, EWVIDCO, Memoranda and Agendas, Network Meeting Reports, Nomination Letters, Department of Community and Preventative Medicine, Operating Budget Figures, Technical Proposals, Hospital Records, NYCOSH Elections, Committee Memoranda, Susan O'Brien Files, Press Statements re: Managed Care, VDT Information and Bibliographies, Reports on VDTs, Technical Reports, National Research Council, Eye Strain Programs, Ergonomic Office Reports and Guidelines, VDT Articles, Job Stress, Lighting, and Hazards
  - Box 25, 1984-1996
    Audio Reels: Asner WMD PSA, Ed Asner Occupational Safety & Health, Audio Cassettes: A. Francisca Ruiz, Flor Reynoso, Matilde Castro, Trina Semorile, US Department of Labor Correspondence, Budget Statistics, NYCOSH Correspondence, FOIA Information, Newspaper Clippings, Work Injuries by Industry Tables, Department of Health Correspondence, Health and Safety Newsletters, Contact Information, OSHA Reform, National COSH 2000 Files, Local COSH Files
  - Box 26, 1983-2003
    AFL-CIO Health and Safety Committee Meeting Agenda, Report of Resolution Compliance, Health Packet and Policy, Shipyard Policy and Hazards, Compensation Forms for Injuries, Newspaper Clippings, Articles for Publication, NYS Labor Department Audit, NYS Labor Religion Coalition, Fliers and Notices, Advert Draft, Union Renewal Letters, Local Correspondence, Center for Occupational Hazard Reports, Pregnancy Rights, Articles and Inspection Schedules, Information in Spanish, Ed Wallace PCB Bill, OSHA Accident and Injury Stats, FOIA, Fact Sheets, Legislative Memos, Ventilation Reports, Subway Reports, WTC, Workplace Violence, NYCOSH Retreats, Safety and Health in the 90s, Infectious Disease in the Workplace, Fighting TB in the Workplace, WPV Regulations and Guidelines, Frank Goldsmith Files, Save OSHA Campaign
  - Box 27, 1990-2005
    Legal Contracts, Riders, and Facsimile, American Journal of Public Health, Newspaper and Magazine Articles, Asbestos Booklet and Workers Compensation Claim, NYCOSH Correspondence, AFL-CIO News and Correspondence, Statewide COSH Newsletters, Occupational Safety and Health Seminar, Legal Correspondence, Workplace Safety Outlines, Indoor Air Pollution Files, Health and Safety Organizing Committee Drive and Fact Sheet, The First National People of Color Environmental Leadership Summit, Mount Sinai Queens Project, State and Federal IMB Workers' Compensation, Clinic Funding, WMD Organizing Packets, Safety and Health Packets, Workers' Memorial Day, Administrative Memoranda, UFCW 174, Dave Newman's Basic Safety Health and Training Materials
  - Box 28, 1979-1984
    Office Automation (General): Information Forms, Correspondence, VDT Booklet, Mailings Correspondence, Order Complaints, NIOSH Materials: Study, Reports, Finding Standards, Photographs, Union Times Newsletters, Articles, and Newspaper Clippings, NYCOSH Newsletters, Publicity and Press Release Materials, Product Surveys, CRT & AFSCME Files, Notes and Questionnaires from VDT Conference, Bell System Guide, OSH Bibliographies, VDT and Radiation Materials and Studies, Committee Reports, Wang CRT Workstation Files, British Society for Social Responsibility in Science Correspondence, Pregnancy and Stress Studies, VDT Committee NIOSH Proposal
  - Box 29, 1986-1989
    Research Files: Stress in the Workplace, Union Membership Forms: Local 400, Amalgamated Clothing & Textile Workers Union, Methodist Hospital, New York Hospital and Care Employees, National Union of Hospital and Health Care Employees, Millinery Workers Union, OSHA Citations, American Federation of Government Employees, Air Transport Workers, Association of Municipal Employees, Bakery, Confectionary, and Tobacco Workers Union, Civil Service Employee Association, Communication Workers of America, NYCOSH Healthcare Fliers, United Auto Workers, Home Care Employees, Real Estate Employees, NYC / Sewage, Department of Traffic Employees, Brooklyn Library Guild, AFSCME District Council 37, Bridge and Tunnel Maintainers, College Assistants, Health & Hospitals, Departments of Parks, Doctors Council, Electrical Employers, Utility Workers, Uniformed Fire Fighters Association
  - Box 30, 1984-2000
    NYCOSH Asbestos Petitions, Intake Forms, Subway Campaign, Correspondence, News Articles, VDT Coalition, Poster Campaign, Agenda, Booklets, Fliers, Newsletters, and Newspaper Clippings, Individual Files, NYCOSH Board Agenda, Westchester Office Lease, Staff Relations and NYCOSH Committee Meeting Minutes
  - Box 31, 1988-1991
    Correspondence Incoming and Outgoing, Pamphlets, Rescue Center Files, Support Letters, Budget and Fiance, EPA Materials
  - Box 32, 1982-1990
    Correspondence, Notes, Union Forms: Motion Picture Studio Mechanics, Projectionists, International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers, Radio & TV Broadcast Engineers, Teamsters, Garment Workers, Iron Workers, Air Transport Workers, American Federation of Musicians, Hyde Park Plumbers, Painters, Paperworkers, American Postal Workers Union, Police, Landlords, Store Owners, Screen Actors Guild, Research and Fliers: Safety and Health on the Job, LIRR Training Manual, Memoranda, Asbestos Training: Exams and Evaluation, Protective Equipment and Emergency Procedures, OSH Government Contacts and Offices, Background Information on Locals, Legal Aid Society Files and Correspondence, Labor International Union of North America, Broadcasting NABET Files, PEF State Insurance Fund, SEIU, Social and Health Workers Files, Interims
  - Box 33, 1987-1990
    Memoranda, Correspondence, Notes, Reports, Newsletters: AHOHC Asbestos Manual: Comments on Drafts, Respirators, WISH/UFT Training, Wisconsin Files, Small-Scale Duration, Training Manual and Asbestos Abatement and Guides, Teachers Union Files, Evaluation Forms, EPA Materials and Training Grant, NYC Certification, Screening and Education Task Force, ACORN Training, New York and New Jersey School Inspections, AHERA Fact Sheets and Compliance
  - Box 34, 1978-1987
    NYCOSH Publications for FIAT Files, Newspapers and Newsletters, Correspondence, Membership Alerts, Handwritten Notes, OCOSH Files, Personnel Records, Committee Files, Political Education Reports, Petitions re: Occupational Safety, Surveys, Photographs, Newspaper Clippings, Workers' Bill of Rights, Fundraising Benefits Photographs and Leaflets, Mailing Lists and Individual Records, VDT Answer Sources, Safety and Health Memos and Briefs, Serials and Booklets, Job Safety Newsletters, Advertising: Offices 80's, VDT Checklist, Legislative Committees, and Foreign Pamphlets, Union Renewal Letters, Science for Citizens Planning Summary
  - Box 35, 1978-1986
    Asbestos Committee Files, Mailing Lists and Personnel Files, Correspondence, Financial Records, Request for Assistance Forms, Price Listings, Union Forms, Organizing Committees, Articles on Union Papers, Management and Business Articles about VDTs, Automated Times: Massachusetts, CWA Packet, United Nations & VDTs, Mount Sinai Newspaper Guild Study, VDT Compensation of Workers, VDT Bookorders, Financial Records, Pamphlets on Occupational Safety, NYCOSH Publication List Correspondence, Metropolitan Outreach Letter, "Health Protection" VDT Article, The Newspaper Guild: VDT - Health Collective Bargaining Kit, NHS Education, NYS Department of Education and Welfare, Urban Environment Correspondence, Reproductive Effects, Mailings, Union Forms, NYCOSH: New Directions Proposal
  - Box 36, 1982-1990
    Leaflets, Correspondence, News, Handwritten Notes, and Reports: White Lung Association, Asbestos Standards, Rulemaking, State Files for Various Asbestos Programs, State Law, Environmental Encapsulating, Asbestos Task Force, ACD Asbestos Reports, EPA Dialogue Process, EPA Draft O&M Program, Revised Drafts, Hearings and Appeals, Press Clippings: Asbestos in Schools
  - Box 37, 1983-1984
    Newsletters: Job Hazards Fact Sheet, NYCOSH Testimonial Dinner, Construction Health Hazards and Prevention, 1983 Long Island Conference, NYCOSH Picnic Materials, Mailings, Safety Reports, Asbestos Conference Packets, Newsletters, Reports, and Literature, Program Notes, Press Releases re: OSHA closings, Public Citizen Litigation (Hazard Communication), Intro to Health Hazards in Theater Crafts, Health Safety in Schools, Product Research, Asbestos Conference Endorsements, Cocktail Fundraisers, VDT Conference, VDT 9 to 5 Campaigns, Copies of "In These Times"
  - Incoming and Outgoing Correspondence, HIV Training Materials, 1992-1993 (Box 38)
  - Subject Files on Occupational Hazards: PCBs, Pesticides, Reproductive Hazards, and Indoor Air Quality, circa 1980s-2000s (Box 39)
  - Subject Files on Occupational Hazards: Asbestos, Sexual Harassment, and Shiftwork, circa 1980s-2000s (Box 40)
  - Subject Files on Occupational Hazards: Asbestos, circa 1980s-2000s (Box 41)
  - Subject Files on Occupational Hazards: World Trade Center, Women's Health, and Young Workers, circa 1980s-2000s (Box 42)
  - Subject Files on Occupational Hazards: Asbestos, circa 1980s-2000s (Box 43)
  - Subject Files on Occupational Hazards: Lead and General Environmental, circa 1980s-2000s (Box 44)
  - Subject Files on Occupational Hazards: Indoor Air Quality and Firefighters, circa 1980s-2000s (Box 45)
  - Subject Files on Occupational Hazards: S (mostly Solvents), circa 1980s-2000s (Box 46)
  - Subject Files on Occupational Hazards: General Environment, Occupational Injuries, and Dyes, circa 1980s-2000s (Box 47)
  - Subject Files on Occupational Hazards: Dyes, Bhopal, AIDS/HIV, and Hazardous Waste, circa 1980s-2000s (Box 48)
  - Subject Files on Occupational Hazards: Reproductive Hazards and Domestic Violence, circa 1980s-2000s (Box 49)
  - Subject Files on Occupational Hazards: Young Workers and Training Materials, circa 1980s-2000s (Box 50)
  - World Trade Center, Immigrant Rights, Legislative Files, and Executive Board Minutes (2002), circa 2000s (Box 51)
  - Testimony and Correspondence File (1994-1998), 1980-1998 (Box 52)
  - Box 53, 1994-2000s
    Correspondence File (1994), Executive Board (includes minutes from 2000-2001), and Legislative Files
  - Box 54, 1994-2000
    Correspondence Files
  - Box 55, 1980s-early 1990s
    Legal Files, Testimony, and Legislative Files
  - Box 56, 1980s-early 2000s
    Newsletters and Press Material
  - Box 57, circa 1990-2009
    New York State AFL-CIO Lobbying Materials, NYCOSH Workers Compensation Committee, and Correspondence
  - Box 58, circa 1990-2009
    Correspondence
  - Box 59, circa 1982-2009
    Conference Materials (Especially Workers Memorial Day)
  - Box 60, circa 1980-2011
    This box contains materials from NYCOSH retreats and assorted news articles, speeches, and correspondence, likely collected by Joel Shufro.
  - Box 61, 1989-2003
    This box contains campaign files related to NYCOSH's advocacy on the issues of workers' compensation, needlestick injuries (as a member of the Needlestick Injury Prevention Coalition), and medical monitoring. Other campaign files pertain to opposition to various OSHA reform bills that proposed to weaken the agency's enforcement powers, the "reinvention" of OSHA in 1995, and the New York State Occupational Safety and Health Training and Education program.
    The box also includes subject files on Presidents Bush and Clinton's relationships to OSHA, specific members of congress, members of affiliated organizations, Workers Memorial Days, asbestos, the Cornell/NYCOSH Occupational Safety and Health Certificate Program, and other topics. There are a few files containing citations and complaints against the Public Employee Safety and Health program (PESH) of the New York State Department of Labor, New York State United Teachers' applications to the New York state Occupational Safety and Health Training grant, and a small amount of NYCOSH office administration material.
  - Ingoing and Outgoing Correspondence, 2003-2011 (Box 62)
  - Box 63, 1981-2011
    This box contains a mockup of a poster for the NYCOSH-sponsored Right to Know Conference in 1981, a poster for the centennial commemoration of the Triangle Shirtwaist Factory fire, and three poster advertisements regarding workers' compensation for 9/11 responders (one in Spanish). There are also several federal, state, and local government proclamations recognizing Workers Memorial Days and Teen Worker Safety Month, as well as a "VDT Safety Now!" button and an informational booklet created by the New York State Public Employees Federation, AFL-CIO on Public Employees Safety and Health (PESH)Act/OSHA standards.
- Series IV: Archived Website, Apr 16, 2009-ongoing
  New York Committee for Occupational Safety and Health (NYCOSH), founded in 1980, is a non-profit coalition of 200 local unions and more than 400 individual workers, physicians, lawyers and other health and safety activists dedicated to the right of worker safety on the job. NYCOSH operates throughout New York City, Long Island and the Lower Hudson Valley. The website gives information and assistance for those injured on the job and other training and safety resources.